In this video, we're going to be taking a look at how
本节视频 主要讨论如何设置 webpack 的生产配置
This is probably one of the most important parts about webpack and doing
这很可能是 webpack 最重要的部分
this step well will mean that we send a great experience to our users.
因为这一步做好了 才能给用户良好的体验
Every front-end developer is concerned with how
每个前端开发者都会关心用户运行自己网站的速度
and the biggest contributors to slow websites are lots of styles,
使网站运行缓慢的最大因素是大量的样式、
lots of JavaScript, and either large or many images.
大量 JavaScript 以及又大又多的图像
Now, to make a website run faster,
想要网站运行更快
we have to make it smaller.
就要使其更小
The smaller the web pages,
网页越小
the fewer bytes that are being sent over the internet to the user;
需要给用户发送的字节数越少
therefore, the faster that the website should be able to run.
运行网站的速度就能越快
When it comes to making a web page smaller,
想要网页更小
we only have two options.
我们只有两个选项
We can either make the webpage smaller by taking away JavaScript or styles or images,
要么删除 JavaScript、样式或图像
or we can make it smaller by compressing both assets into
要么通过压缩资源使其转为一个较小的格式
a smaller format and our webpack config can actually do a lot of that minifying for us.
而 webpack 配置就可以为我们完成很多缩小化的任务
Webpack minifies all of our JavaScript by default when we choose production mode.
处于生产模式时 webpack 会自动缩小化所有的 JavaScript
But all of our styles are a different story.
但是对于样式来说 是不同的处理方法
Right now in the webpack dev server,
现在在 webpack 开发服务器
it takes all of our styles and puts them into the main.js
它会将样式全部放入 main.js 文件
file and then adds them into our HTML via inline styles.
然后通过内联样式放入 HTML
The problem with that is that inline styles are slow,
这样处理的问题是 内联样式太慢
and to be most efficient,
要提高效率
we need to take all of our styles and move them into a CSS file that can be minified.
我们需要将样式全部移入可以缩小化处理的 css 文件中
So we're going to add a mini CSS extract plug-in that's going to do those steps for us.
要完成这些步骤 需要先添加 mini-css-extract-plugin 插件
By now you're pretty familiar with adding a new plugin to your webpack config but,
现在 你已经对在 webpack 配置中添加插件的操作很熟悉了
just quickly I have already added the minify CSS extract plug-in.
不过还是快速过一遍 我已经添加了 mini-css-extract-plugin
I've installed it via NPM,
通过 npm 进行了安装
and I've instantiated it here in my plugins list.
在 plugins 列表中进行了实例化
One of the unique things about
mini-css-extract-plugin 插件比较特殊的是
the mini CSS extract plugin is that it gives us a loader that
它提供了一个加载器
we can use much like we did with the sass and
我们可以像上一节在开发配置中
CSS loaders in the previous lesson in our dev config.
使用 sass 加载器和 css 加载器那样设置
So I'm going to add a new set of rules that
所以要添加一个新的 rule
will handle all of our style sheets for production.
处理生产的所有样式表
Here, you can see that we are again looking for a scss file extension.
这里可以看到仍然在查找 scss 文件扩展名
But instead of the CSS style-loader that we used in the dev config,
不过与开发配置中使用 style-loader 不同
style-loader here was taking all of our styles and loading them into inline styles.
style-loader 的作用是将所有的 css 样式转换为内联样式
But like we said before inline styles are slow,
如之前所说 内联样式很慢
and so we actually want to extract
所以我们想要提取 (extract) 所有 css
our CSS into its own file that's going to be added to the distribution folder.
单独作为一个文件添加到分发文件夹中
So now that we have that setup in our webpack production config,
现在设置好了 webpack 生产配置
we can come here and run our build prod command.
我们可以到终端中运行 build prod 命令
Now, make sure that you have
请确保自己已经安装好了 mini-css-extract-plugin
run this command and then see a new output in
我们应该可以在运行该命令后看到
our distribution folder which is this main.css file.
分发文件夹中多了一个输出 main.css 文件
When you look at the CSS file,
打开这个 css 文件
it has all of the styles from all of our style sheets concatenated together.
其中包括了我们所有的样式表
I don't have very many styles but imagine that this file is say 5,000 lines long.
现在没有特别多的样式 不过假设该文件有 5000 行
Now, this is easily human-readable,
现在是易于阅读的形式
which means that it hasn't been minified yet.
也就是说还没进行缩小化处理
All we're doing at this point is extracting this CSS that would
我们目前做的只是将所有 css 提取出来
normally go into our main.js file if we were running the webpack dev server.,
这些原本在开发模式下应该放入 main.js 的 css
but now we've brought it out into our own main.css.
现在这些代码全部被放入了单独的 main.css 文件中
Now, this is the file that we're going to
这就是我们需要为用户进行缩小化处理的文件
To do that last minification step,
要完成最终的最小化步骤
we're going to add a new piece to our webpack prod config file.
要在 webpack prod 配置中添加一个新的内容
Now, this is the optimization attribute,
也就是 optimization (优化) 属性
and what it's going to do is allow us to run minimizing actions on certain files.
这个设置的作用就是使我们可以对特定文件执行缩小化操作
In this case, we're going to use two new plugins to do our optimization work.
在当前示例中 还需要添加两个新的插件完成优化操作
The first one is the tertiary plug-in and the second is the optimized CSS assets plugin.
一个是 terser-plugin 另一个是 optimize-css-assets-plugin
First things first, we're going to install all of the plug-ins that we need.
首先 要先安装这两个插件
So I have my cursor and optimize plugins ready to go,
所以我安装好了 terser (紧凑) 和 optimize (优化) 插件
and now I'm going to add the required statements for both of those new plug-ins.
现在需要为这两个插件添加 require 语句
One cool thing about the tertiary and optimize plugins is that you can
关于这两个插件 比较棒的一点是
see we are initializing them here instead of in the plugins list.
可以直接在这里实例化 而不用在 plugins 中编写
You would know to do that by reading
你可以在这两个插件的 GitHub 指导说明中了解这一点
you can just now put them here.
现在只需要直接使用即可
Now that we've set up those two new plug-ins,
设置好两个新的插件之后
we can rerun our config and we should see the modified CSS file on the other side.
重新运行配置 应该可以看到缩小化的 css 文件
Now, we can see that our main.css file is, in fact, minified.
现在打开 main.css 文件 可以看到确实缩小了
It's no longer the friendly human-readable format
不再是易于阅读的格式
but it's taken a lot of space out of our file.
将空格全部删除了
Some minimizers will even go through and shorten your class names to be
某些缩小器甚至还会将类名称修改为一个字母
one letter or do other enhancements to make the code as short as possible.
或者做出一些其他的缩小化改善
Now, it's a good rule of thumb that if you come across a built file like this,
分享一条经验 遇到这样缩小化的构建文件时
and it's a clue that you shouldn't edit this file because it's
不要进行修改
going to be overwritten every time that they rebuild the styles.
因为这些修改每次重新构建都会被覆盖
So, in general, don't modify a built file.
简而言之 不要修改构建后文件
It isn't any fun anyway.
这没什么好处